franchising.com 2019-06-30

# Franchising.com Privacy Policy

We have prepared this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy" or "Policy") to explain to you how we collect, use, and share information and Personal Data (as defined under applicable law) we obtain through your use of the Internet sites, applications and online services ("Services") that are operated by, controlled by or affiliated with Franchise Update Media, including without limitation Franchising.com (collectively, "we," "us" or "our"). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected through Franchising.com and via direct communications between you and Franchise Update Media, and does not cover any information collected at any other website, application or otherwise by us (unless specifically stated), including when you call us, write to us, or communicate with us in any manner other than through Franchising.com. By using Franchising.com, you consent to such collection, use and sharing of your information and Personal Data and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We will only process your Personal Data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. For the purposes of UK and EU data protection legislation, the data controller is Franchise Update Media of 6489 Camden Ave. Suite 204, San Jose CA 95120 USA.

## Information We Automatically Collect

We and our third-party service providers (including any third-party content, advertising, and analytics providers) automatically collect certain information from your device or web browser when you interact with Franchising.com to help us understand how our users use Franchising.com and to target advertising to you (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as "Usage Data"). For example, each time you visit Franchising.com we and our third-party service providers automatically collect your IP address, mobile device identifier or other unique identifier, browser and computer type, access time, the Web page you came from, the URL you go to next, the Web page(s) that you access during your visit and your interaction with content or advertising on Franchising.com.

We and our third-party service providers use such Usage Data for a variety of purposes including to diagnose problems with our servers and software, to administer Franchising.com, to gather demographic information and to target advertising to you on Franchising.com and elsewhere online. Accordingly, our third-party advertising networks and ad servers will also provide us with information, including reports that will tell us how many ads were presented and clicked on Franchising.com in a manner that does not identify personally any specific individual. The Usage Data we collect is generally non-identifying, but if we associate it with you as a specific and identifiable person, we will treat it as Personal Data.

## Cookies/Tracking Technologies

We use tracking technologies, such as cookies, local storage, and pixel tags.

### WHAT ARE COOKIES?

For almost any modern website to work properly, it needs to collect certain basic information on its users. To do this, a site will create files known as cookies – which are small text files – on its users’ computers and other devices. These cookies are designed to allow Franchising.com to recognize its users on subsequent visits, or to authorize other designated websites to recognize these users for a particular purpose.

Cookies do a lot of different jobs which make your experience of the Internet much smoother and more interactive. For instance, they are used to remember your preferences on sites you visit often, to remember your user ID and the contents of your shopping baskets, and to help you navigate between pages more efficiently. They also help ensure that the advertisements that you see online are more relevant to you and your interests. Some data collected is designed to detect browsing patterns and approximate geographical location to improve user experience.

Some websites may also contain images called "web beacons" (also known as "clear gifs"). Web beacons only collect limited information, including a cookie number, a timestamp, and a record of the page on which they are placed. Websites may also carry web beacons placed by third party advertisers. These beacons do not carry any personally identifiable information and are only used to track the effectiveness of a particular campaign (for example by counting the number of visitors).

Information collected by cookies is now classed as personal data.

### HOW DO WE USE COOKIES?

We collect a number of cookies from our users for various reasons, not least to track our own performance – but also to let us serve you content tailored to your own specifications, hopefully improving your overall experience of Franchising.com. Amongst other things, the cookies we use allow users to register to make comments, allow us to calculate how many visitors we have and how long they stay on our site.

We do our utmost to respect users’ privacy. We use cookies to monitor and improve our services, but they do also allow us to sell advertising campaigns that are tailored to your interests and reading behavior on our website, which helps keeps our content free to our readers. We sometimes include links on our site to goods and services offered by third parties and we may be paid some commission if you subsequently decide to make a purchase. Cookies may be used to track your visits to third party sites to help ensure that we are paid the correct amounts. Please note that these commercial arrangements do not influence our editorial content in any way.

We believe that your experience of the site would be adversely affected if you opted out of the cookies we use.

### WHAT TYPES OF COOKIE ARE THERE AND WHICH ONES DO WE USE?

There are two  types of cookie:

  * **Persistent cookies** remain on a user’s device for a set period of time specified in the cookie. They are activated each time that the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.
  * **Session cookies** are temporary. They allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close the browser window. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

Cookies also have, broadly speaking, four different functions and can be categorized as follow: ‘strictly necessary’ cookies, ‘performance’ cookies, ‘functionality’ cookies and ‘targeting’ or ‘advertising’ cookies.

Strictly necessary cookies are essential to navigate around a website and use its features. Without them, you wouldn’t be able to use basic services like registration or shopping baskets. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you’ve been on the internet.

Examples of how we use ‘strictly necessary’ cookies include:

  * Setting unique identifiers for each unique visitor, so site numbers can be analysed.
  * Allowing you to sign in to the Franchising.com website as a registered user.

**Performance cookies** collect data for statistical purposes on how visitors use a website, they don’t contain personal information such as names and email addresses, and are used to improve your user experience of a website.  

Here are some examples of how we use performance cookies:

  * Gathering data about visits to the website, including numbers of visitors and visits, length of time spent on the site, pages clicked on or where visitors have come from.
  * For comparison with other websites using data collected by industry-accepted measurement and research companies.

Information supplied by performance cookies helps us to understand how you use the website; for example, whether or not you have visited before, what you looked at or clicked on and how you found us. We can then use this data to help improve our services.  We generally use independent analytics companies to perform these services for us and when this is the case, these cookies may be set by a third party company (third party cookies).

If you have registered with the website we can combine the data from the web analytics services and their cookies with the information you have supplied to us, so that we can make your experience more personal by recommending certain articles to you based on your reading behavior or tailoring your emails with content you might find more interesting.  We would only do this if you have given us permission to communicate with you. Sometimes the data used from the web analytics companies has been collected before you registered or signed in. In these cases, if we use this data to identify you, we use it only in accordance with our privacy notice.

**Functionality cookies** allow users to customize how a website looks for them: they can remember usernames, language preferences and regions, and can be used to provide more personal services like local weather reports and traffic news.

Here are some examples of how we use functionality cookies:

  * Storing your user preferences on Your Account page
  * Remembering if you’ve been to the site before so that messages intended for first-time users are not displayed to you.

**Advertising and targeting cookies** are used to deliver advertisements more relevant to you, but can also limit the number of times you see an advertisement, and be used to chart the effectiveness of an ad campaign by tracking users’ clicks. They can also provide security in transactions. They are usually placed by third-party advertising networks with a website operator’s permission, but can be placed by the operator themselves. They can remember that you have visited a website, and this information can be shared with other organisations, including other advertisers. They cannot determine who you are though, as the data collected is never linked to your profile.

The two main ways we use advertising and targeting cookies are set out below:

  * **Interest-based advertising** (or online behavioral advertising) is where cookies are placed on your device by our third party service providers which remember your web browsing activity and group together your interests in order to provide you with targeted advertisements which are more relevant to you when you visit Franchising.com.  Your previous web browsing activity can also be used to infer things about you, such as your demographics (age, gender etc.). This information may also be used to make the advertising on Franchising.com more relevant to you.
  * **‘Retargeting’** is a form of interest-based advertising that enables our advertising partners to show you advertisements selected based on your online browsing activity away from the website.  This allows companies to advertise to people who previously visited their website. These cookies will usually be placed on your device by third-party advertising networks and we have listed the main third party networks we work with below.

Without these cookies, online advertisements you encounter will be less relevant to you and your interests.

### HOW DO I CONTROL MY COOKIES?

You should be aware that any preferences will be lost if you delete all cookies and many websites will not work properly or you will lose some functionality. We do not recommend turning cookies off when using our website for these reasons.

Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but you can alter the settings of your browser to erase cookies or prevent automatic acceptance if you prefer. Generally you have the option to see what cookies you’ve got and delete them individually, block third party cookies or cookies from particular sites, accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is issued or reject all cookies. Visit the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu on your browser to change settings, and check the following links for more browser-specific information.

### ENABLING THE DO NOT TRACK (DNT) WEB BROWSER FEATURE

We instead suggest using the Do Not Track (DNT) feature built into your web browser. Franchising.com honors DNT requests and will not track anyone who has this setting toggled to an on state. You can learn more about the DNT feature in your browser by visiting: <https://allaboutdnt.com/>

### MANAGING PERFORMANCE COOKIES

It is possible to opt out of having your anonymised browsing activity within websites recorded by performance cookies.

Franchising.com uses the following companies and you can opt out of their cookies by clicking on the relevant links. Please note that this will take you to the relevant third party’s website and generate a ‘no thanks’ cookie, which will stop any further cookies being set by those third parties.

Don’t forget that by not allowing performance cookies, this stops us from being able to learn what people like or don’t like about our website so that we can make it better.

Google Analytics: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout%20)

Quantcast: <https://www.quantcast.com/en-uk/opt-out/>

### MANAGING ADVERTISING COOKIES

Please note that if you want to opt out from receiving targeted advertising, this does not mean that you will receive less advertising when you use our website. This just means that the advertising you see will not be as customised to you.

You can visit the Internet Advertising Bureau’s consumer advice site, [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices](http://youronlinechoices.com/).  This will give you a list of all cookies that are currently set on your device and how to opt out of each of them.  Please note that this list will contain more networks than just found on Franchising.com.

We have also set out links below to some of the specific partners we work with who set cookies on our websites, and therefore on your computer, each of which have instructions on how to opt out of their cookies.

Google – <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html>

### USER AGREEMENT

You can change your consents to the use of cookies at any time by clicking on our <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>. If you choose not to receive our cookies, we cannot guarantee that your experience will be as fulfilling as it would otherwise be.

## Information You Choose To Submit

You can visit Franchising.com without telling us who you are or revealing any information by which someone could identify you as a specific, identifiable individual (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as "Personal Data"). If, however, you wish to register to become a member of Franchising.com, you are required to provide certain Personal Data (for example, your name and e-mail address), and you must also provide a user name and password. We use your Personal Data to fulfil your requests for products and services, to improve our Services, to contact you from time to time, with your consent, about us and our products and services, and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. In addition, you are required to provide certain Personal Data when you submit a job application and supporting materials. Where you submit a job application on behalf of another person, you confirm that you have made that person aware of how we collect, use and share their Personal Data, the reason you have provided it, how they can contact us, the terms of this Privacy Policy and related policies and that they have consented to such collection, use and sharing. You can also choose to submit or we may collect additional information about yourself, such as demographic information (for example your gender, birth date, or zip code) and information about your preferences and interests. Failure to provide any required Personal Data will prevent us from being able to provide the services you request (e.g., member registration or submission of job application) or otherwise inhibit our ability to provide the services.

We refer collectively to all information we collect that is not Personal Data, including Usage Data, demographic data and de-identified Personal Data, as "Non-Personal Data". If we combine Non-Personal Data with Personal Data, we will treat the combined information as Personal Data under this Privacy Policy.

You also can choose to submit your alias, bio, email, photos or any other information that you would like to share with other users of Franchising.com (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as "User Submissions").

Personal Data, Non-Personal Data, and User Submissions are referred to in this Privacy Policy collectively as "User Information."

## Information We Receive From Other Sources

We supplement the information we collect with outside records in order to learn more about our users, to better tailor the content and offers we show you, and for other purposes. We receive this information about you from public sources or third parties, including without limitation consumer data resellers and advertisers. We combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through Franchising.com. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to the combined information.

## Information Use

We use the information we collect, including Personal Data and Usage Data:

  * to enable you to use our Services, to create an account or profile, to process information you provide via our Services (including verifying that your email address is active and valid) and to process your transactions;
  * to provide related customer service and care, including responding to your questions, complaints, or comments and sending surveys (with your consent) and processing survey responses;
  * to provide you with information, products, or services that you have requested;
  * to receive and process job applications for jobs with us;
  * with your consent, to provide you with information, products, or services that we otherwise believe will interest you, including special opportunities from us and our third-party partners;
  * to tailor content, recommendations, and advertisements we and third parties display to you, both on Franchising.com and elsewhere online;
  * for internal business purposes, such as to improve our Services;
  * to administer and process contests, sweepstakes, and promotions;
  * to contact you with administrative communications and, in our discretion, changes to our Privacy Policy, Terms of Use, or any of our other policies;
  * to comply with regulatory and legal obligations; and
  * for purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, and as further described in this Privacy Policy.

Franchising.com contains integration with social networks and other platforms in which information is shared between us and such platforms. For example, if you create or login to your account through a third-party social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, email address, account information, photo and friends lists, and other information in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site. If you visit our Services on a device through which you also interact with social networks or if you interact with us through a social media function such as a plug-in (for example, a Facebook "like" button) then you permit us to have ongoing access to, to use and to store information from your social network profile (such as your name, email address, your friend list, photo, age, gender, location, birthday, social networking ID, current city, and the people/sites you follow) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you don't want a social network to collect the information about you as described above, or you don't want a social network to share it with us, please review the privacy policy, privacy settings and instructions of the applicable social network before you visit and use our Services.

## Our Information Sharing Practice

  * (a) Generally. We share Non-Personal Data, including Usage Data, de-identified Personal Data and aggregated user statistics, with third parties in our discretion. We share User Information, including Personal Data, as otherwise described in this Policy, and under the following circumstances:
  * (b) Service Providers. From time to time, we enter into relationships with third parties who provide services to us (for example, analytics companies, advertisers and ad agencies, data management and storage services or credit card processing services, sweepstakes or contest prize fulfillment). In those circumstances, we disclose User Information so that such service providers perform those services. These service providers are only permitted to use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to enable them to provide their services to us. They are required to follow our express instructions and to comply with appropriate security measures to protect your Personal Data. In particular, our sites use certain Google analytics and other services, and certain pages use the Google AMP Client ID API, each of which enable collection and sharing of your information (including Personal Data) with Google for further use. For specific information on Google usage and how to control it, please see How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps and Google’s Privacy Policy.
  * (c) Third-Party Marketing. You will have a choice (opt-in or opt-out) before we share your information with third parties for marketing purposes. Provided that you have chosen to receive marketing messages from third parties, we share your information (including Personal Data) with third parties for those third parties' own direct marketing purposes. Please note, messages delivered from a third-party will subject you to the third-party's privacy policy. We also match your email address with third parties with whom you have also consented to share your email address and use such match to deliver custom offers or emails to you on Franchising.com and off Franchising.com provided you have consented to receiving such offers or emails.
  * (d) Change of Control. In the event we go through a business transition (such as a merger, acquisition by another company, bankruptcy, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process), your Personal Data will likely be among the assets transferred. By providing your Personal Data, you agree that we can transfer such information in those circumstances without your further consent. Should such a business transition occur, we will make reasonable efforts to request that the new owner or combined entity (as applicable) follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your Personal Data. If your Personal Data would be used contrary to this Privacy Policy, we will request that you receive prior notice.
  * (e) Other Disclosure Scenarios. We reserve the right, and you hereby expressly authorize us, to share User Information: (i) in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; (ii) if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or property; (iii) if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding significant abuse of Franchising.com infrastructure or the Internet in general (such as voluminous spamming, denial of service attacks, or attempts to compromise the security of information); (iv) to protect and defend our legal rights or property, our services or their users, or any other party, and to protect the health and safety of our users or the general public; and (v) to our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us (in which case we will require such entities to honor this Privacy Policy).

## Anonymous Data

When we use the term "anonymous data," we are referring to data and information that does not permit you to be identified or identifiable, either alone or when combined with any other information available to a third-party. We may create anonymous data from the Personal Data we receive about you and other individuals whose Personal Data we collect. Anonymous data will include analytics information and information collected by us using cookies. We make Personal Data into anonymous data by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the data personally identifiable to you. We use this anonymous data to analyze usage patterns in order to make improvements to our Services.

## Public Information

If you identify any User Information as public, you are authorizing us to share such information publicly. For example, you can elect to make certain of your User Submissions (such as your alias, bio, email or photos) publicly available. Also, there are areas of Franchising.com (for example, message boards, discussion rooms, and other online forums) in which you are able to post information that automatically will be available to all other users of Franchising.com. By choosing to use these areas, you understand and agree that anyone can access, use, and disclose any information that you post to those areas.

## Users Outside of the United States and Consent to Transfer

Franchising.com operates in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please be aware that information you provide to us will be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States. By using Franchising.com or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws are not as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside or are a citizen such as the European Union. You understand that the U.S. government can obtain access to the Personal Data you submit if necessary for investigative purposes (e.g., terrorism investigation). We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We use appropriate and suitable safeguards for transferring your Personal Data to the U.S. (e.g., standard contractual clauses issued by the European Commission, which can be accessed [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)).

## California Privacy Rights

As stated elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, Franchise Update Media does not share Personal Data with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83, unless we give you choice (opt-in or opt-out) before sharing with those third parties.

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please contact us at Franchise Update Media of 6489 Camden Ave. Suite 204, San Jose CA 95120 USA. You must put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. Please note that we will not accept inquiries via the telephone, email, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labelled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

## How We Respond to "Do Not Track (DNT)" Signals

Internet browsers can be configured to send "Do Not Track" signals to the online services that you visit. California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Franchising.com responds to "Do Not Track" browser settings.

Franchising.com proudly supports the DNT feature of most web browsers and will disable it's marketing, social, and statistical tracking when the Do Not Track feature is active.  To find out more about "Do Not Track," please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

## ADVERTISING

  * (a) Generally. We use other companies under agreements with us to serve third-party advertisements when you visit and use Franchising.com. These companies collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to Franchising.com and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use tracking technologies to collect this information. Other companies' use of their tracking technologies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.
  * (b) Targeted Advertising. In order to serve offers and advertisements that may be of interest to our users, we display targeted advertisements on Franchising.com, or other digital properties or applications in conjunction with our content, based on information provided to us by our users and information provided to us by third parties that they have independently collected. We do not provide Personal Data to our advertisers when you interact with an advertisement.
  * (c) Your Ad Choices. Some of the third-party services providers and/or Advertisers may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") or the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the "opt-out" procedures of NAI members. You can opt-out of our use of your Web site viewing behavior data to serve you interest-based advertising on third-party sites and email newsletters here <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.
  * If you are accessing Franchising.com through an application (i.e., mobile phone or tablet) you can download the AppChoices application from your device's application store (i.e., Google Play, Apple App Store, and Amazon Store). This DAA application allows participating companies to offer an opt-out of customized advertisements that are based on predictions about your interests generated from your application usage. For more information, visit http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices.
  * Please note opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while online or on your device.
  * (d) Mobile. We may from time to time offer certain location or pinpoint based services, such as location assisted navigation instruction. If you elect to use such location-based services, we must periodically receive your location in order to provide such location-based services to you. By using the location-based services, you authorize us to: (i) locate your hardware; (ii) record, compile and display your location; and (iii) publish your location to third parties designated by you by means of location publication controls available within the applications (for example, settings, user preferences). As part of the location-based services, we also collect and store certain information about the users who elect to use such location-based services, such as a device id. This information will be used to provide you the location-based services. We use third-party providers to help provide location-based services through mobile systems (unless you opt out of such location-based services with such providers) and we provide the information to such providers to enable them to provide their location-based services, provided that such providers use the information in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

## Choice/Opt-Out From Communications

We offer you the opportunity to manage your communications from us. Even after subscribing to one or more newsletters and/or opting in to one or more offers to receive marketing and/or promotional communications from us or our third-party partners, users may elect to modify their preferences by logging into their [Franchising.com Account](https://www.franchising.com/login/) going to their "User Settings" page anytime , visiting the "[Subscription Management](https://subscribe.franchising.com/unsubscribe.html)" page, or by simply clicking the "Unsubscribe" link provided in an email or communication received.

Even if you do opt-out of marketing and newsletter emails, we reserve the right to send you transactional and administrative emails including those related to your Franchising.com account which may include notifications of suspicious activity, password change notifications, security updates, changes to our privacy policy, and other administrative communication. If you no longer wish to receive those emails you can "Delete your Account" under the User Settings option.

## Retaining, Modifying and Deleting Your Personal Data

You may access the information we hold about you. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below. If you would like to update, correct, modify or delete from our database any Personal Data you previously submitted to us, please let us know by accessing and updating your profile. If you delete certain information you may not be able to order services in the future without re-submitting such information. We will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Also, please note that we will maintain Personal Data in our database whenever we are required to do so by law.

Please note that we need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (for example, when you enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such promotion). We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

## Security

We have implemented commercially reasonable and appropriate technical and organizational security measures to help protect your Personal Data from accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, misuse, or unauthorized access or disclosure; unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your User Information, we cannot guarantee its security. You use Franchising.com and provide us with information at your own initiative and risk. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us at security@franchising.com.

## Links

Franchising.com contain links to other websites that we do not control, and they contain videos, advertising and other content hosted and served by third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third-party.

## Children's Privacy

Franchising.com are intended for a general audience and are not intended for and should not be used by children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and we do not target Franchising.com to children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below. We will delete such information from our files as soon as reasonably practicable.

## Sensitive Personal Data

Subject to the following paragraph, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive personal data as this term is defined under applicable data protection and privacy laws (for example, social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through Franchising.com or otherwise to us.

If you send or disclose any sensitive personal data to us, you consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data, you must not submit such content to our Services.

## Changes

We update this Privacy Policy from time to time in our discretion and will notify you of any material changes to the way in which we treat Personal Data, by posting a notice on relevant areas of Franchising.com. We will also provide notice to you in other ways in our discretion, such as through contact information you have provided. Any updated version of this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy unless otherwise specified. Your continued use of Franchising.com after the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy (or such other act specified at that time) will constitute your consent to those changes. However, we will not, without your consent, use your Personal Data in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time your Personal Data was collected.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [privacy@franchising.com](mailto:privacy@franchising.com).  
If you have security concerns please contact: [security@franchising.com](mailto:security@franchising.com).

**Franchising.com | Franchise Update Media**  
P.O. Box 20547  
San Jose, CA 95160  
USA  
(408) 402-5681
